John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - Having New England fathers, 1934; MS007.001.003.00454; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 004. Published in Address to the living, p. 14; Poet's Gold (New York: Devin-Adair, 1956) p. 388; Yankee Poetry Chapbook, p. 20, Summer 1934. The date has been estimated revisions in 4:37; 10:034, p. 65; 10:038, p. 10, duplicate in 10:010, p. 52
  - Hearing music, 1940-02-01; MS007.001.003.00455; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 005. Annotated Published in The symbols, p. 10; Virginia Quarterly Review, 22:383, July 1946; Voices, 102:15, Summer 1940. Printed on Christmas card for 1946. duplicate in 3:5, revisions in 4:112; 6:036; 10:033, p. 48; 10:035, p. 32; 11:002, p. 48
  - Heart's almanac, 1946; MS007.001.003.00456; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 006. Published in Westminster Magazine, 35:14, Autumn 1946. The date has been estimated revisions in 6:033, 7:009, and 10:033, p. 35
  - Herself, 1949-04-01; MS007.001.003.00457; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 007. revision in 4:115 is annotated Published in The double root, p. 28; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 213 duplicate in 3:7, revision in 4:115, sound recording in 64:001
  - I can hardly wait, MS007.001.003.00458; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 008. Annotated Published in The symbols, p. 22. revisions in 8:044 and 10:035, p. 43
  - I live in a world, 1946; MS007.001.003.00459; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 009. Annotated Published in Christian Register, 125:164, April 1946. The date has been estimated revision in 4:059
  - Incredible greeting, 1932; MS007.001.003.00460; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 011. Annotated: "To appear in Poetry" Published in Address to the living, p. 40; Poetry, 40:314-15, September 1932. revisions in 5:9; 10:010, p. 23; 10:034, p. 25
  - Journey's end, 1938; MS007.001.003.00461; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 012. Published in Christian Science Monitor, June 16 1938. The date has been estimated revision in 6:029
  - The known world [Map of my country], 1939; MS007.001.003.00462; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 014. Notes in 10:010 made by Anna Beatrice Murphy. Revision in 10:019 is partial: it contains only parts 3, 4, and 5. Revision in 10:010, p. 152 is partial: it contains only beginning of part 1. Revision in 11:001 has extensive typewritten annotations by Holmes. Revision in 11:002 is annotated. Published in Map of my country, p. 3; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 214; Within the Americas (Boston: Ginn, 1949) p. 9-10; This Is America (New York: Pocket, 1950) p. 6; Parts III-V published in American Prefaces, 6:235-38, Spring 1941; New Yorker, 15:24, April 22, 1939; Tripolitan, 7:5-6, July 1955; Part 1 published in Senior Scholastic, 44:20, February 7-12, 1944. The date has been estimated revisions in 3:59; 10:010; 10:019; 10:010, p. 152; 11:001; 11:002
  - The landmark, 1936; MS007.001.003.00463; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 015. Published in Address to the living, p. 38.; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1936 and Yearbook of American Poetry. (New Yorkm: Poetry Digest Association, 1937), p. 73; Atlantic, 158:92-92, July 1936. The date has been estimated revisions in 10:010, p. 108 and 10:038, p. 27
  - Rock in the ground, 1937; MS007.001.003.00464; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 015. Published in Address to the living, p. 94; Yankee, 3:6, January 1937. The date has been estimated revision in 10:010, p. 110
  - Do you know?, 1937; MS007.001.003.00465; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 015. Published in Address to the living, p. 96; Horn Book Magazine, 13:78, March - April 1937. The date has been estimated revision in 10:010, p. 101
  - The laws [Order clearly asking], 1958; MS007.001.003.00466; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 016. Duplicate in 5:100 dated 1961. Revision in 11:003, p. 9 is titled: "Order clearly asking" Published as "Order clearly asking" in The fortune teller, p. 11; Published in English Leaflet, 59:26, Spring 1960; Poetry, 95:279-80, February 1960. Printed as Christmas card for 1958. The date has been estimated duplicates in 5:100 and 7:013, revisions in 10:037, p. 128 and 11:003, p. 9
  - Let them stand: for Robert Nichols, geologist, 1946; MS007.001.003.00467; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 017. Published in Tuftonian 6, no. 1:44, 1947; University of Kansas City Review, 13:41, Autumn 1946. The date has been estimated revision in 10:035, p. 113
  - The letter, 1953; MS007.001.003.00468; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 018. Annotated Published in The fortune teller, p. 20; Reader and Writer (Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1954) p. 161-62; New Poems by American Poets: Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1953) p. 87. The date has been estimated duplicates in 10:035, p. 70 and 10:037, p. 43, revision in 11:003, p. 18, sound recording in 64:001
  - Letter to my mother, 1952; MS007.001.003.00469; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 019. Revisions in 3:20 are heavily annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 76; Ladies' Home Journal, 69:140, March 1952. The date has been estimated revisions in 3:20; 5:10; 5:11; 10:033, p. 11; 10:035, p. 114-118; 10:037, p. 20
  - Lines beginning "I", 1955-09-01; MS007.001.003.00470; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 021. Annotated: originally in Atlantic June 1940 Published as 'Lines beginning I, and others' in Saturday Review of Literature, 29:46, April 27, 1946. revisions in 6:070 and 10:037, p. 32
  - Address to the living, 1934; MS007.001.003.00471; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 022. Published in Address to the living, p. 3; Atlantic, 153: 706-7, June 1934. The date has been estimated revisions in 3:23; 3:24; January 10, 1934, 3:25; 10:010, p. 58; 10:034, p. 136; 10:038, p. 11
  - Alarm, 1948; MS007.001.003.00472; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 027. Published in The double root, p. 17; New Yorker, 24:32, October 3, 1948. The date has been estimated duplicates in 3:27 and 10:033, p. 39
  - Along the row, 1927; MS007.001.003.00473; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 028. Published in Along the row, p. 3; Eleusis of Chi Omega, 55:208-09, May 1953; Tufts Weekly, November 9 1927, p. 1. The date has been estimated
  - Anecdote of Robert Frost, 1946; MS007.001.003.00474; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 029. Revision in 3:30 is annotated: This is something that happened to Frost two years ago; he told me about it. Revision in 10:035, p. 188 is annotated. Published in The symbols, p. 13; Forum, 105:461, January 1946. The date has been estimated revisions in 3:30 and 10:035, p. 188, duplicate in 10:035, p. 33
  - The architects, 1933-01-11; MS007.001.003.00475; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 031. Published in Address to the living, p. 45; American Poetry Journal, p. 10, January 1935; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:283, July 1937. revisions in 7:014; 10:010, p. 42 and 10:034, p. 39
  - As the heart beats, 1933; MS007.001.003.00476; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 032. Published in Address to the living, p. 9; American Poetry Journal, p. 30, September 1933. revisions in 3:32; 7:014; 10:034, p. 37; 10:038, p. 18
  - Auction, 1948-02-01; MS007.001.003.00477; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 033. Published in The double root, p. 60; A Way of Knowing (New York: Crowell, 1959) p. 88; Saturday Review of Literature, 31:20, October 9, 1948.
  - Birthday: at Richard Eberhart's fiftieth, MS007.001.003.00478; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 035. Revision in 10:036, p. 7 is annotated: certain sections are crossed out. Published in The fortune teller, p. 16 revisions in 10:035, p. 4; 10:036, p. 7; 10:037, p. 54; 11:003, p. 14; sound recording in 64:001
  - Boy in August, 1927-05-01; MS007.001.003.00479; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 036. Published in Tuftonian, 2:22, October 1927. duplicate in 3:36
  - Boy to anyone, 1954-11-09; MS007.001.003.00480; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 037. Published: New York Herald-Tribune, November 9, 1954
  - Bucyrus [Booth, Bucyrus & Brazil], 1951-01-01; MS007.001.003.00481; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 038. Revision in 10:035, p. 98 is annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 26; The Criterion Book of Modern American Verse (New York: Criterion Books, 1956) p. 228; The Faber Book of Modern American Verse (London: Faber and Faber, 1956) p. 228; New Poems by American Poets: Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1953) p. 86. revisions in January 1951, 4:73; January 1951 5:080; 10:035, p. 98; 10:036, p. 93; 11:003, p. 24, duplicate in 10:037, p. 46, sound recording in 64:001
  - Business-like letter, MS007.001.003.00482; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 039. Annotated Published in The double root, p. 22; Harper, 192:560, June 1946. revision in 10:033, p. 33
  - Carry me back, 1954-07-18; MS007.001.003.00483; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 041. Revisions in 10:036, p. 71, 72, 74, 76, 78, & 80 are annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 85; Best Poems of 1956 (Stanford, Calif.: Stanford University Press, 1957) p. 42; New Poems of American Poets: No. 2 Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1957) p. 74; New Yorker, 32:28, July 28, 1956. revisions in July 18, 1954, 5:85; 10:036, p. 69; 10:036, p. 71; 10:036, p. 72; 10:036, p. 73; 10:036, p. 74; 10:036, p. 76; 10:036, p. 78; 10:036, p. 80; 10:037, p. 68; 11:003, p. 67, sound recordings in 64:001 and 67:001
  - The flowers (first version) [Home from Woodlawn], 1961; MS007.001.003.00484; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961". Revision in 9:093 dated: January 1960. Revision in 10:037, p. 164 is titled: "Home from Woodlawn" revisions: retitled Home from Woodlawn, 3:42; 5:2; 5:3; 9:093; 10:037, p. 164, duplicate in 10:037, p. 149, sound recording in 67:001
  - The certainty, 1961; MS007.001.003.00485; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New poems, 1961". Revision in 10:037, p. 161 is annotated. Published in Poetry in Crystal (New York: Corning Glass Works, 1963) p. 38; Tufts Alumni Review, 9:38, Summer 1963. duplicate in 4:67, revisions in 4:68; 4:69; 4:70; 4:71; 10:037, p. 161
  - Edward Hicks's old picture, 1961; MS007.001.003.00486; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961"; Revisions in 4:77, 4:80, and 4:81 are annotated. Published in Harper, 224:84, February 1962. revisions in 4:77; 4:78; 4:79; 4:80; 4:81; 5:90; 10:037, p. 163
  - Faithful reader, 1961; MS007.001.003.00487; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961". Revision in 8:065 is annotated. Published in Harper, 225:81, July 1962. revisions: February 1961, 5:89; 6:020; 6:021; 6:022; 6:023; 8:065; 8:066; 10:037, p. 167
  - The new porch, 1961; MS007.001.003.00488; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961." Revision in 9:043 titled: The lower middle classes. Revision in 9:056 is annotated. revisions in 9:043; 9:056; 9:057; and 10:037, p. 168
  - Two of a kind, 1961-04-01; MS007.001.003.00489; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961". Revision in 6:099 dated April 1961. Published in Saturday Review, 46:32, February 9, 1963. revisions in 6:098; April 1961, 6:099; 10:037, p. 165
  - In the Gardner museum, 1961; MS007.001.003.00490; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961" revisions in 9:029 and 9:030, duplicate in 10:037, p. 165
  - The war between the states, 1961; MS007.001.003.00491; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961". Revisions in 9:094, 9:095 are annotated. revisions in 6:103, 6:104, 9:094, 9:095, 9:096 and duplicate in duplicate in 10:037, p. 167
  - Margaret's choice, 1961; MS007.001.003.00492; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 042. Annotated: "New Poems, 1961" Published in New Yorker, 37:62, October 7, 1961. duplicates in January 1961, 5:99 and 10:037, p. 160
  - Everyone knows about Boston, MS007.001.003.00493; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 045. Published in Fair warning, p. 49 revision in 10:010, p. 104
  - Mailman blues, 1951-03-01; MS007.001.003.00494; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 046. Revision in 5:61 is titled: P.O. Blues Published in The fortune teller, p. 63; University of Kansas City Review, 20:56-7, Autumn 1953. revisions in 5:22; March 1951, 5:61; 7:013; 10:035, p. 101; 10:037, p. 61; 11:003, p. 53
  - The mask the living wear, 1933-01-01; MS007.001.003.00495; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 047. Published in Address to the living, p. 63; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:45, May 1937; Poetry, 53:245, February 1934. revisions in 3:48; 7:014; 10:010, p. 45; 10:017; 10:034, p. 53
  - Memorandum of agreement, 1949; MS007.001.003.00496; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 049. Published in The double root, p. 56; Epoch, 2:110, Winter 1949. revision in 10:018 and sound recording in 64:001
  - Memory [Memory's color], 1933-02-01; MS007.001.003.00497; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 052. revisions in 5:25 and 10:010, p. 47, duplicate in 10:034, p. 55
  - Mercator, MS007.001.003.00498; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 053. Published in Epoch, 2:111, Winter 1949. duplicate in 10:018
  - Metaphor for my son, 1942-03-01; MS007.001.003.00499; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 054. Published in Map of my country, p. 48; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 217; The Sound of Wings (New York: Holt, 1957) p. 278; Yale Review n s, 32:518-19, March 1943. duplicates in 3:54 and 11:002, p. 50
  - The mirror, 1962; MS007.001.003.00500; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 040. Published in The double root, p. 29; New York Times Book Review, July 22 1962, p. 2. revision in 3:55, duplicates in 4:72 and 3:40
  - Montaigne's pate, 1947-02-01; MS007.001.003.00501; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 056. Revision 5:029 dated 1947. Revision in 9:049 dated January 1947. Revision in 9:049 titled: Montaigne. Published in The double root, p. 36; Epoch, 1:88-89, Winter 1946. Printed on Christmas card for 1959. revisions in 5:29; January 1947, 9:049; 10:033, p. 16A
  - Misery [Essay on misery], 1939; MS007.001.003.00502; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 058. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939" Published as Essay on misery in Map of my country, p. 94; New Yorker, 15:24, September 30, 1939. revision in 11:002, p. 91, sound recording in 64:001
  - People in the street [At thirty-five], 1939; MS007.001.003.00503; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 058. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939" Published in Map of my country, p. 96; New Yorker, 15:25, March 11, 1939. revisions in 5:056; 8:026; 8:027; 10:010, p. 148; 11:002, p. 93
  - Do not pity the young, 1939; MS007.001.003.00504; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 059. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939" Published in Map of my country, p. 38, Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1938-1942 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Paebar, 1942), p. 218; Atlantic, 163:761, June 1939. revisions in 10:010, p. 149 and 11:002, p. 40
  - West mountain spring [West mountain water], 1939; MS007.001.003.00505; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 059. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939". Some sections in duplicate 10:010, p. 147 are crossed out. Published as "West mountain water" in Map of my country, p. 81; Lyric, 19:53, Winter 1940. revisions in 6:057 and 11:002, p. 77, duplicate in 10:010, p. 147
  - The second wonder, 1939; MS007.001.003.00506; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 060. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939". Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Map of my country, p. 79; Yale Review n s, 28:292-93, December 1938. revisions in 3:94; 5:070; 5:071; (only page 2) 5:072; 10:006; 10:010, p. 140; 11:002, p. 75
  - The place he seeks, 1939; MS007.001.003.00507; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 060. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939"; Revision in 6:052 is annotated on back; Revision in 8:001 entitled "Speed John Smith"; Revision in 8:002 (annotated); Revision in 10:010 has a section crossed out. Published in Christian Register, 123:280, August 1944. duplicate in 6:052, revisions in 8:001; 8:002; 10:010, p. 141; 10:035, p. 161
  - The enduring, 1939; MS007.001.003.00508; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 060. Annotated: "New Poems: Spring 1939" Published in Map of my country, p. 39; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1938-1942 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Paebar, 1942), p. 217; Atlantic, 166:169, August 1940. revisions in 10:002 and 11:002, p. 41
  - New Proverbs, MS007.001.003.00509; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 061. Annotated Published in The symbols, p. 35; Published in Epoch, 2:111, Winter 1949. revisions in 7:059; 10:033, p. 20; 10:035, p. 51
  - The new view [Youth and age], 1940-02-01; MS007.001.003.00510; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 062. Revision in 9:020 is titled: Youth and age. Revision in 9:020 is dated February 1940. Published in Map of my country, p. 84; An Introduction to Literature (Boston: Little, Brown, 1961) p. 292; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 219; American Prefaces, 6:232, Spring 1941. duplicate in 5:45, revisions in 6:060; February 1940, 9:020; 10:019; 11:002, p. 80
  - Noah his ark, 1948-02-23; MS007.001.003.00511; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 063. Published in The double root, p. 54; Hopkins Review, 2:47-48, Spring 1949.
  - Northward letter [In this moment], 1932; MS007.001.003.00512; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 064. Revisions in 6:010 & 7:047 & 7:048 is titled: In this moment. Revision in 7:047 is dated May 20, 1932 Published in Address to the living, p. 20; Virginia Quarterly Review, 11:395-96, July 1935. The date has been estimated revisions in 6:010; May 20, 1932, 7:047; 7:048; 10:010, p. 34, 10:034, p. 13, duplicate in 7:047
  - Nothing told me, MS007.001.003.00513; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 065. Published in English Saturday Review, 155:14, January 7, 1933. duplicates in 10:010, p. 29 and 10:034, p. 10, revisions in 10:034, p. 85 and 10:035, p. 132
  - Old men and young men, MS007.001.003.00514; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 066. Published in Fair warning, p. 54; Address to the living, p. 81; A Way of Knowing (New York: Crowell 1959) p. 216; The New Yorker Book of Verse (New York: Harcourt, Brace, 1935) p. 191; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:45, May 1937. revisions in 3:67; 6:002; 10:010, p. 55; 10:017; 10:034, p. 69, duplicate in 3:66
  - One day's rain, 1952-05-01; MS007.001.003.00515; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 068. Annotated. Revision in 10:035, p. 73 is annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 94; Quarterly Review of Literature 7, no 3:194, n d; University of Kansas City Review, 20:62, Autumn 1953. duplicates in May 1952, 3:068 and 10:037, p. 39, revisions in 10:035, p. 16; 10:035, p. 73; 11:003, p. 74, and sound recording in 64:001
  - Ordeal by love, 1932-08-01; MS007.001.003.00516; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 069. Published in Voices, 74:8, February-March 1934. revisions in 3:70; 9:081; 10:010, p. 56; 10:034, p. 30; 10:035, p. 139, and duplicate in 10:034, p. 141
  - The overgrown back yard, 1953-06-01; MS007.001.003.00517; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 071. Annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 89; The Criterion Book of Modern American Verse (New York: Criterion Books, 1956) p. 228; The Faber Book of Modern American Verse (London: Faber and Faber, 1956) p. 228-29; New Poems by American Poets: Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1953) p. 87; Literary Cavalcade, 10:19, January 1948; New Yorker, 29:36, May 30, 1953. duplicates in 3:71; 10:035, p. 72; 10:037, p. 44, revision in 11:003, p. 70, sound recording in 64:001
  - Panther in my mind [The panther in the mind], 1933-02-01; MS007.001.003.00518; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 072. Published in Address to the living, p. 13.; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1936 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Poetry Digest Association, 1937), p. 75; American Mercury, 37:419, April 1936; Fiction Parage and Golden Book Magazine, 4:250, December 1936; Brooklyn Times Union, December 27 1936. revisions in 4:50; 7:014; 10:010, p. 48; 10:034, p. 57; 10:038, p. 9
  - The people's peace, 1937; MS007.001.003.00519; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 073. Set to music as hymn of same title in Hymns for the Celebration of Life, Boston: Beacon Press, 1964. Published in Map of my country, p. 97; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1937, (New York: Paebar, 1938), p. 78; Home and Holiday Verse (New York: Halcyon House, 1939) p. 664; Ficiton Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:528, September 1937; New York Times, December 5 1943; Waterbury, Connecticut American, August 5 1937. Printed on Christmas card for 1937. revisions in 5:057; 7:008; 10:010, p. 142; 11:002, p. 94
  - Peter at his mirror, MS007.001.003.00520; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 074. Published in Thirty Years of Tufts Verse; An Anthology (Cambridge, MA: Carra-Christian, 1931) p. 40; Poetry, 30:264, August 1927, Tuftonian n s, 1:140, January 1927. revisions in 4:51; 10:010, p. 8; 10:035, p. 119, and duplicates in 10:034, p. 3 and 10:034, p. 112
  - But choose, 1948-07-01; MS007.001.003.00521; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 040. Published in The double root, p. 61; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 220; Kenyon Review, 11:115-17, Winter 1949. revision in 4:72
  - The pity is, MS007.001.003.00522; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 076. Published in Fair warning, p. 33; Address to the living, p. 69; American Poetry Journal, p. 7, September 1934. revisions in 4:52 and 10:034, p. 67, duplicate in 10:010, p. 54
  - The place of light, 1937; MS007.001.003.00523; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 078. Published in Map of my country, p. 41; Yale Review n s, 26:703, June 1937. Printed on Christmas card for 1938. duplicate in 10:010, p. 124 and revision in 11:002, p. 43
  - Portrait, MS007.001.003.00524; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 080.
  - Open letter [Christmas letter] [From tonight], 1944-12-01; MS007.001.003.00525; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 081. Revision located 8:045 entitled: Christmas letter Published as From tonight in The symbols, p. 17. revisions in 8:045; 10:033, p. 8; and 10:035, p. 38
  - Pour down, MS007.001.003.00526; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 082. Two copies, one handwritten in calligraphy. Revision in 10:035, p. 99 is annotated. Published in New Poems by American Poets: Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1953) p. 85; Quarterly Review of Literature 7, no 3:193, n d. revisions in 10:035, p. 99 and 10:037, p. 55
  - Puritan ancestor, MS007.001.003.00527; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 083. Published in Map of my country, p. 78; American Mercury, 41:365, July 1937. revisions in 10:010, p. 123 and 11:002, p. 74, sound recording in 64:001
  - Questions for the candidate, MS007.001.003.00528; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 084. Published in The double root, p. 65. duplicates in 3:84 and 10:033, p. 21
  - Reading aloud, 1949-04-01; MS007.001.003.00529; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 085. Published in The double root, p. 67; Saturday Review of Literature, 33:22, April 1, 1950. duplicate in 3:085
  - The rebellion, 1932; MS007.001.003.00530; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 086. Published in Address to the living, p. 43; Voices, 74:11, February-March 1934. Fall 1932 revisions in 3:87; 3:88; 3:89; 3:90; 4:23; 10:010, p. 40; 10:010, p. 41; 10:034, p. 36; 10:034, p. 114
  - The saving grace, 1949-12-01; MS007.001.003.00531; Holmes, John (Box 3)